Hello English learners.
各位英语学习者，大家好。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we're going to be taking you to the airport.
今天我们要带你去机场。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to listen as a man checks in at the airport and deals with his luggage.
我们会听一位男士在机场办理登机手续和处理行李的过程。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to be looking at a lot of great stuff that can help you the next time you
所以我们会看到很多很棒的内容，能帮到你下次
are at the airport at the check-in counter.
在机场值机柜台时。
So why don't we take a look at one word that we're going to preview today in Vocabulary
那我们不如先看看今天在“词汇预览”中要预览的一个词。
Preview.
词汇预览。
Vocabulary Preview.
We're going to hear this guy say, I'd like to check three pieces.
我们会听到这个人说：“我想托运三件。”
He's going to check three pieces of what?
他要托运三件什么？
Pieces of luggage.
三件行李。
So when we talk about luggage, we can say pieces of luggage.
所以当我们谈论行李时，可以说“pieces of luggage”。
That's right.
没错。
Luggage is a non-count noun.
“Luggage”是不可数名词。
So you can't say one luggage, two luggages, three luggages.
所以你不能说“one luggage”、“two luggages”、“three luggages”。
That's wrong.
那是错的。
Right.
对。
So we use pieces of luggage.
所以我们用“pieces of luggage”。
Okay.
好的。
He's going to check three pieces of luggage.
他要托运三件行李。
Very good.
很好。
Let's listen to our dialogue for the first time.
让我们第一次听对话。
We're going to see what happens with this guy at the airport and with his pieces of
我们会看看这个人在机场和他的行李发生了什么。
luggage.
行李。
Next please.
下一位。
Hello, sir.
您好，先生。
May I see your passport, please?
请出示您的护照好吗？
Yes.
好的。
Here you go.
给你。
Will you be checking any bags today?
今天要托运任何行李吗？
Yes.
是的。
I'd like to check three pieces.
我想托运三件。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
Airline policy only allows two pieces of checked luggage at 20 kilograms each plus one piece
航空公司政策只允许托运两件行李，每件20公斤，外加一件
of carry-on luggage.
随身行李。
I will have to charge you extra for the additional suitcase.
您需要为额外的行李箱支付费用。
What?
什么？
Why?
为什么？
I'm taking an intercontinental flight.
我坐的是洲际航班。
I'm flying 16,000 kilometers.
我要飞16,000公里。
How am I supposed to take only two 20 kilo bags?
我怎么可能只带两个20公斤的包？
That's absurd.
这太荒谬了。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
There's nothing I can do.
我无能为力。
You cannot board the flight with that large bag either.
您也不能带着那个大包登机。
Carry-on bags must fit in the overhead compartment or under your seat.
随身行李必须能放进头顶行李架或座位下面。
That bag is clearly too big.
那个包明显太大了。
Now I see.
现在我明白了。
You charge next to nothing for an international ticket.
国际机票你们几乎不收费。
When it comes to charging for any other small thing, you charge an arm and a leg.
但一提到其他小东西收费，你们就狮子大开口。
So tell me, miss, how much will I have to pay for all of this?
所以告诉我，小姐，所有这些我要付多少钱？
Let's see.
让我看看。
$625 US dollars.
625美元。
That's more than my round-trip ticket!
那比我的往返机票还贵！
All right, well, that's a whole lot of money, isn't it?
好吧，那可真是一大笔钱，对吧？
Well, I think it's a very common situation.
嗯，我觉得这是很常见的情况。
I'm sure many of our listeners can relate to this situation.
我相信很多听众都能感同身受。
Overweight charges are pretty expensive.
超重费相当贵。
Very high.
非常高。
I know from personal experience.
我亲身经历过。
But that's not what we want to talk about now.
但这不是我们现在要谈的。
We want to talk about some really useful vocabulary in Language Takeaway.
我们想在“语言精华”中讨论一些非常有用的词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言精华。
All right, on Language Takeaway today, we have five words.
好的，今天的“语言精华”里，我们有五个词。
So why don't we start with the first one?
那我们不如从第一个开始？
So the woman asked, will you be checking any bags today?
所以那位女士问：“今天要托运任何行李吗？”
Will you be checking any bags today?
今天要托运任何行李吗？
To check bags.
托运行李。
Right.
对。
So the verb to check.
所以动词“to check”。
It means to give your bags to the airline, to register them.
意思是把你的行李交给航空公司，进行登记。
Okay, so that's what happens with your luggage.
好的，这就是你的行李的处理方式。
You check them, so basically they become responsible for your bags.
你托运它们，基本上他们就对你的行李负责了。
Right.
对。
It reminds me of checking in to a hotel.
这让我想起入住酒店。
Right, very similar.
对，很相似。
When you go to a hotel, you register at the hotel.
你去酒店时，在酒店登记。
You check in.
你办理入住。
In this case, you just check your luggage.
在这种情况下，你只是托运你的行李。
You don't check in your luggage.
你不是办理行李入住。
Right.
对。
Okay, so check luggage.
好的，所以是“check luggage”。
So he wanted to check three pieces of luggage, and he also had carry-on luggage.
所以他想要托运三件行李，他还有随身行李。
Carry-on luggage.
随身行李。
Carry-on.
随身携带的。
So carry-on luggage, it's pretty simple.
“Carry-on luggage”很简单。
That's right, you carry it on yourself.
没错，你自己随身携带。
Exactly, you carry it on to the plane.
对，你把它带上飞机。
Now we can talk about carry-on luggage, right?
现在我们可以说“carry-on luggage”，对吧？
Or carry-on bag.
或者“carry-on bag”。
Right, or a carry-on suitcase.
对，或者“carry-on suitcase”。
A very small suitcase that can fit under your seat.
一个很小的行李箱，能放在座位下面。
Exactly.
没错。
All right, so carry-on luggage.
好的，所以是“carry-on luggage”。
Now he was traveling on an intercontinental flight.
他当时乘坐的是洲际航班。
Intercontinental.
洲际的。
We have two words there, inter.
这个词有两部分，“inter”。
Between.
在……之间。
Between, right?
在……之间，对吧？
And continental.
和“continental”。
So this sounds like continent.
所以听起来像“continent”（大陆）。
Okay, so he's traveling maybe from Asia to North America.
好的，所以他可能从亚洲飞到北美。
Okay, intercontinental.
好的，洲际的。
He's trying to board this intercontinental flight.
他试图登上这趟洲际航班。
So to board a flight.
所以是“board a flight”。
Board a plane.
登机。
Board a train.
上火车。
All right, so basically it means to...
好的，所以基本上意思是……
To get on.
上（交通工具）。
To get on a vehicle.
上交通工具。
Okay, so I can say board the ship, board the car.
好的，所以可以说“board the ship”、“board the car”。
No.
不行。
No?
不行？
No.
不行。
But board the train.
但可以说“board the train”。
Board the train.
上火车。
Board the bus.
上公交车。
All aboard.
全体上车。
That's right, that's why in movies you see that somebody will yell all aboard.
没错，这就是为什么在电影里你会看到有人喊“全体上车”。
Yeah.
嗯。
In the train station, right?
在火车站，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
All aboard.
全体上车。
Okay, so board a vehicle and our last phrase for today, overhead compartment.
好的，所以是“board a vehicle”，我们今天的最后一个短语是“overhead compartment”。
Overhead compartment.
头顶行李架。
All right, let's break this phrase down.
好的，我们来分解这个短语。
Overhead.
“Overhead”。
So that's on top of your head, right?
所以是在你头顶上方，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Above you.
在你上面。
Yeah, and the compartment is a place where you can put something and store it.
嗯，“compartment”是一个可以放东西并储存的地方。
Kind of like a box.
有点像盒子。
Right.
对。
Yeah.
嗯。
So overhead compartment, that big box where you put your bags and your purse or whatever
所以“overhead compartment”，就是飞机上那个大箱子，你放包、钱包或其他东西的地方。
on an airplane.
嗯。
Mm-hmm.
Very similar to, for example, an overhead projector.
和“overhead projector”很像。
Right, so that's the machine that puts an image or a picture on a wall, like sometimes
对，那是一种把图像或图片投射到墙上的机器，比如有时在会议上能看到。
you see them in meetings.
对，因为图像在你头顶上方而且很大，所以叫“overhead projector”。
Right, so because the image is over your head and it's big, it's called an overhead projector.
好的，所以是一些很棒的语言。
Okay, so some great language.
Why don't we hear it again in context by listening to the dialogue for the second time?
我们不如再听一遍对话，在上下文中感受一下？
Next, please.
下一位。
Hello, sir.
您好，先生。
May I see your passport, please?
请出示您的护照好吗？
Yes, here you go.
好的，给你。
Will you be checking any bags today?
今天要托运任何行李吗？
Yes, I'd like to check three pieces.
是的，我想托运三件。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
Airline policy allows only two pieces of checked luggage at 20 kilograms each, plus one piece
航空公司政策只允许托运两件行李，每件20公斤，外加一件
of carry-on luggage.
随身行李。
I will have to charge you extra for the additional suitcase.
您需要为额外的行李箱支付费用。
What?
什么？
Why?
为什么？
I'm taking an intercontinental flight.
我坐的是洲际航班。
I'm flying 16,000 kilometers.
我要飞16,000公里。
How am I supposed to take only two 20-kilo bags?
我怎么可能只带两个20公斤的包？
That's absurd.
这太荒谬了。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
There's nothing I can do.
我无能为力。
You cannot board the flight with that large bag either.
您也不能带着那个大包登机。
Carry-on bags must fit in the overhead compartment or under your seat.
随身行李必须能放进头顶行李架或座位下面。
That bag is clearly too big.
那个包明显太大了。
Now I see.
现在我明白了。
You charge next to nothing for an international ticket.
国际机票你们几乎不收费。
But when it comes to charging for any other small thing, you charge an arm and a leg.
但一提到其他小东西收费，你们就狮子大开口。
So tell me, miss, how much will I have to pay for all this?
所以告诉我，小姐，所有这些我要付多少钱？
Let's see.
让我看看。
$625 US dollars.
625美元。
No.
不。
That's more than my round-trip ticket.
那比我的往返机票还贵。
All right.
好吧。
So I think it's a little bit more clear now.
所以我觉得现在更清楚一些了。
And with this, it's time for us to take a look at some great phrases in putting it together.
有了这个，是时候看看“融会贯通”里的一些好短语了。
Putting it together.
融会贯通。
So this guy was pretty angry about this airline policy.
所以这个人对航空公司的政策非常生气。
And he said, how am I supposed to?
他说：“我怎么可能？”
How am I supposed to?
我怎么可能？
Okay.
好的。
So before we get into explaining this, why don't we listen to a couple of examples so
在我们解释这个之前，不如先听几个例子，
we can try and understand what it means.
这样我们就能试着理解它的意思。
Example one.
例子一。
How am I supposed to fit the dog in the car?
我怎么可能把狗塞进车里？
There are 10 people in there already.
里面已经有十个人了。
Example two.
例子二。
How is she supposed to get to work if her car's in the shop?
如果她的车在修理厂，她怎么去上班？
Example three.
例子三。
How are we supposed to know the answer to that?
我们怎么可能知道那个答案？
It's impossible.
那是不可能的。
Okay.
好的。
So I can understand that it means, how can I do this?
所以我能理解它的意思是，我该怎么做？
Right.
对。
How do you expect me to do this?
你指望我怎么做？
How is it possible for me to do this?
我怎么可能做到？
Very good.
很好。
It's a phrase you use when you're frustrated, right?
这是一个你在沮丧时用的短语，对吧？
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
When you're maybe a little bit frustrated or you're maybe nervous of something that
当你有点沮丧，或者对某件事感到紧张时，
you can't do or don't know how.
你做不到或不知道怎么做。
Yeah.
嗯。
This phrase, it's not impolite, but it sort of gives the idea that you're challenging
这个短语不算不礼貌，但有点暗示你在
the other person a little bit.
挑战对方。
Maybe.
也许吧。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
So a good phrase that you can use in different situations and you can try and mix it up with
所以这是一个可以在不同场合使用的好短语，你可以尝试搭配
different verbs, right?
不同的动词，对吧？
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
Now let's take a look at our next phrase.
现在我们来看看下一个短语。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
There's nothing I can do.
我无能为力。
So basically, the woman can't help the man, even though he's insisting and he's pushing
所以基本上，这位女士帮不了那位男士，尽管他坚持
that he wants another solution.
想要另一个解决方案。
Yeah.
嗯。
Right.
对。
So finally, she says, I'm sorry, there's nothing I can do.
最后，她说：“对不起，我无能为力。”
So we use this phrase when someone's pushing you too much, right?
所以我们在别人逼得太紧时用这个短语，对吧？
Right.
对。
And you would use it only in that situation towards the end because it is a little bit...
而且你只在那种情况下，在最后才用，因为它有点……
It's strong.
语气很强。
It's not in plight, but it's just, you're saying, you know what, I'm sorry, there's
它不算不礼貌，但就是你在说：“你知道吗，对不起，
I can't do anything about it.
我对此无能为力。”
Now let's move on to our third phrase.
现在我们来看第三个短语。
You charge next to nothing.
你收费几乎为零。
Next to nothing.
几乎为零。
All right.
好的。
So we're talking about charging.
所以我们在谈论收费。
We're talking about money.
我们在谈论钱。
Why don't we listen to some examples of what this next to nothing phrase means?
我们为什么不听一些例子，看看这个“几乎为零”的短语是什么意思？
Example one.
例子一。
Do you like my new house?
你喜欢我的新房子吗？
It was so cheap that it almost cost next to nothing.
它便宜得几乎没花什么钱。
Example two.
例子二。
Let's go to Thailand.
我们去泰国吧。
Tickets cost next to nothing right now.
现在机票几乎不花钱。
Example three.
例子三。
The real estate agent charged me next to nothing for his commission, so I got a really good
房地产经纪人收我的佣金几乎为零，所以我得到了一个非常好的
deal.
交易。
So when something costs next to nothing, it's really cheap, right?
所以当某样东西“几乎不花钱”时，它真的很便宜，对吧？
It's really cheap, or you consider it to be cheap.
真的很便宜，或者你认为它便宜。
And now for our last phrase, it's the complete opposite of next to nothing.
现在来看最后一个短语，它和“几乎为零”完全相反。
Right.
对。
Charge an arm and a leg.
收费贵得离谱。
An arm and a leg.
贵得离谱。
All right.
好的。
So this means it's really expensive.
所以这意味着它真的很贵。
It's so expensive.
太贵了。
It's like giving your arm and your leg.
就像要付出你的胳膊和腿。
Right.
对。
To pay for it.
来支付它。
Yeah.
嗯。
Very good.
很好。
So next to nothing, really cheap.
所以“几乎为零”是很便宜。
An arm and a leg, really expensive.
“贵得离谱”是很贵。
Can we look at the use here?
我们能看看这里的用法吗？
All right.
好的。
So in the dialogue we heard, you charge an arm and a leg, but we can also say it costs
在对话中我们听到“你收费贵得离谱”，但我们也可以说“它花费
an arm and a leg.
贵得离谱”。
Right.
对。
Because we are referring to money.
因为我们指的是钱。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
So some great phrases here.
所以这里有一些很棒的短语。
Now I think it's time we listen to our dialogue one more time.
现在我想是时候再听一遍我们的对话了。
What?
什么？
Why?
为什么？
I'm taking an intercontinental flight.
我坐的是洲际航班。
I'm flying 16,000 kilometers.
我要飞16000公里。
How am I supposed to take only two 20 kilo bags?
我怎么能只带两个20公斤的包？
That's absurd.
这太荒谬了。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
There's nothing I can do.
我无能为力。
You cannot board the flight with that large bag either.
你也不能带着那个大包登机。
Carry-on bags must fit in the overhead compartment or under your seat.
随身行李必须放在头顶行李架或座位下面。
That bag is clearly too big.
那个包显然太大了。
Now I see.
现在我明白了。
You charge next to nothing for an international ticket.
国际机票你收费几乎为零。
When it comes to charging for any other small thing, you charge an arm and a leg.
但一提到其他小东西收费，你就贵得离谱。
So tell me, miss, how much will I have to pay for all of this?
所以告诉我，小姐，所有这些我要付多少钱？
Let's see.
让我看看。
625 US dollars.
625美元。
That's more than my round trip ticket.
那比我的往返机票还贵。
Okay.
好的。
So airline policies, luggage, it's always a problem, right?
所以航空公司的政策、行李，总是个问题，对吧？
Most of the time you always end up paying overweight when you travel.
大多数时候你旅行时总是要付超重费。
Yeah.
嗯。
I know that this happened to me once and it was really expensive.
我知道这发生在我身上一次，真的很贵。
Really?
真的吗？
What happened?
发生了什么？
I was flying on an intercontinental flight from India back to Europe and I had too many
我坐洲际航班从印度回欧洲，带了太多
extra bags, but I really needed to bring them.
额外的行李，但我真的需要带它们。
And so it cost me $6,000.
结果花了我6000美元。
$6,000.
6000美元。
Yeah.
嗯。
Wow.
哇。
So my credit card was pretty maxed out after that.
所以之后我的信用卡几乎刷爆了。
That's incredible.
真难以置信。
Yeah.
嗯。
Well, I'm sure many of our users probably suffered similar experiences like this.
嗯，我相信很多用户可能都有过类似的经历。
So please come to our website and share it with us at EnglishPod.com.
所以请来我们的网站，在EnglishPod.com上分享。
That's right.
没错。
Marco and I are always around to answer your questions.
马可和我随时都在回答你们的问题。
So please check us out and thanks for downloading you guys.
所以请来看看我们，谢谢你们的下载。
Until next time.
下次见。
Goodbye.
再见。